independenttravelcats.com 2019-06-25

# Privacy Policy for Independent Travel Cats - Independent Travel Cats

Independent Travel Cats is owned by Travel Cats Media Ltd, a company registered in England and Wales, with company number 11524454\. The registered company address is: Travel Cats Media Ltd, C/o High Royd Business Services Limited, B B I C, Innovation Way, Barnsley, South Yorkshire,S75 1JL, England.

This privacy policy has been compiled to help you understand how we store and use your data, and specifically that data which is personally identifiable. This is so you are fully informed and understand your choices, and is in line with both US Privacy law and the European GDPR law.

Please read our privacy policy carefully to get a clear understanding of how we collect, use, protect or otherwise handle your Personally Identifiable Information in accordance with our website.

 **What personal information do we collect from the people that visit our website?**

When leaving a comment on our site,  we ask for your name and email address, as well as a comment. We do this so we can personalise our response to you, ensure you are a real person (and therefore reduce spam comments), and also enables us to notify you of a response should you opt in to a response. We store your e-mail and name so we can do this, as well as an IP address and browser information.

 **How do we store your data?**

When you leave a comment on our site, we store your data on our secure server in line with local regulations. If you have left a comment or comments, you can request to receive an exported file of the personal data we hold about you, including any data you have provided to us. You can also request that we erase any personal data we hold about you. This does not include any data we are obliged to keep for administrative, legal, or security purposes. Please send requests of this nature to jessica@independenttravelcats.com

 **When do we collect information?**

We collect information from you when you subscribe to our newsletter or enter information on our site, for example to leave a comment.

 **How do we use your information?**

We may use the information we collect from you when you leave a comment or sign up to our newsletter in order to:

  * Personalize the newsletter
  * Notify you of comment replies if you opt-in to recieving replies (you can unsubscribe from this feature at any time by notifying us)
  * Administer a contest, promotion, survey or other site feature.
  * To send any e-mails you sign up for

 **How do we protect visitor information?**

  * Our website is scanned on a regular basis for security holes and known vulnerabilities in order to make your visit to our site as safe as possible.
  * We use regular Malware Scanning.
  * We use an SSL certificate
  * We only provide articles and information

 **Transfer of Data Outside the EU**

We may store and process your information through third-party services in the US and other jurisdictions. As a result, we may transfer your personal information to a jurisdiction with different data protection and government surveillance laws than your jurisdiction. If we transfer information about you outside the EU, we will do so to organisations which are Privacy Shield certified or which are considered to have adequate data protection controls for the purposes of GDPR.

 **Do we use ‘cookies’?**

Yes. Cookies are small files that a site or its service provider transfers to your computer’s hard drive through your Web browser (if you allow) that enables the site’s or service provider’s systems to recognize your browser and capture and remember certain information.  They are also used to help us understand your preferences based on previous or current site activity, which enables us to provide you with improved services. We also use cookies to help us compile aggregate data about site traffic and site interaction so that we can offer better site experiences and tools in the future.

 **We use cookies to:**

  * Keep track of advertisements.
  * Compile aggregate data about site traffic and site interactions in order to offer better site experiences and tools in the future. We may also use trusted third party services that track this information on our behalf.

You can choose to have your computer warn you each time a cookie is being sent, or you can choose to turn off all cookies. You do this through your browser (like Internet Explorer) settings. Each browser is a little different, so look at your browser’s Help menu to learn the correct way to modify your cookies.

If you disable cookies, some features will be disabled. It won’t affect the users experience but cookies make your site experience more efficient and some of our services will not function properly. for users in the EU, you have the option to control specific non-essential cookies, either through the “privacy settings” button at the bottom of the page, or when you first visit the site.

 **Third Party Disclosure**

We do not sell, trade, or otherwise transfer to outside parties your personally identifiable information unless we provide you with advance notice. This does not include website hosting partners and other parties who assist us in operating our website, conducting our business, or servicing you, so long as those parties agree to keep this information confidential. We may also release your information when we believe release is appropriate to comply with the law, enforce our site policies, or protect ours or others’ rights, property, or safety.

However, non-personally identifiable visitor information may be provided to other parties for marketing, advertising, or other uses.

 **Third party links**

Occasionally, at our discretion, we may include or offer third party products or services on our website. These third party sites have separate and independent privacy policies. We therefore have no responsibility or liability for the content and activities of these linked sites. Nonetheless, we seek to protect the integrity of our site and welcome any feedback about these sites.

 **Google**

Google’s advertising requirements can be summed up by Google’s Advertising Principles. They are put in place to provide a positive experience for users. You can see them [here](https://support.google.com/adwordspolicy/answer/1316548?hl=en).

We use Google AdSense Advertising on our website, through our advertising partner, Mediavine.

Google, as a third party vendor, uses cookies to serve ads on our site. Google’s use of the DART cookie enables it to serve ads to our users based on their visit to our site and other sites on the Internet. Users may opt out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the Google ad and content network privacy policy.

 **We have implemented the following:**

 **•** Remarketing with Google AdSense

 **•** Google Display Network Impression Reporting

 **•** DoubleClick Platform Integration

We along with third-party vendors, such as Google use first-party cookies (such as the Google Analytics cookies) and third-party cookies (such as the DoubleClick cookie) or other third-party identifiers together to compile data regarding user interactions with ad impressions, and other ad service functions as they relate to our website.

 **Opting out:**

Users can set preferences for how Google advertises to you using the Google Ad Settings page. Alternatively, you can opt out by visiting the Network Advertising initiative opt out page or permanently using the Google Analytics Opt Out Browser add on.

 **California Online Privacy Protection Act**

CalOPPA is the first state law in the nation to require commercial websites and online services to post a privacy policy. The law’s reach stretches well beyond California to require a person or company in the United States (and conceivably the world) that operates websites collecting personally identifiable information from California consumers to post a conspicuous privacy policy on its website stating exactly the information being collected and those individuals with whom it is being shared, and to comply with this policy. – See more at: http://consumercal.org/california-online-privacy-protection-act-caloppa/#sthash.0FdRbT51.dpuf

 **According to CalOPPA we agree to the following:**

  * Users can visit our site anonymously
  * Once this privacy policy is created, we will add a link to it on our home page, or as a minimum on the first significant page after entering our website.
  * Our Privacy Policy link includes the word ‘Privacy’, and can be easily be found on the page specified above.

 **Users will be notified of any privacy policy changes:**

 **•** On our Privacy Policy Page

 **Users are able to change their personal information:**

 **•** By emailing us, jessica@independenttravelcats.com

 **How does our site handle do not track signals?**

We do our best to honor do not track signals and do not track, plant cookies, or use advertising when a Do Not Track (DNT) browser mechanism is in place. We have no control over third party advertising cookies on our site.

 **Does our site allow third party behavioral tracking?**

Yes we allow third party behavioral tracking. For countries covered by laws such as GDPR, any tracking is explicit and opt-in.

 **COPPA (Children Online Privacy Protection Act)**

When it comes to the collection of personal information from children under 13, the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA) puts parents in control. The Federal Trade Commission, the nation’s consumer protection agency, enforces the COPPA Rule, which spells out what operators of websites and online services must do to protect children’s privacy and safety online.

We do not specifically market to children under 13.

 **Fair Information Practices**

The Fair Information Practices Principles form the backbone of privacy law in the United States and the concepts they include have played a significant role in the development of data protection laws around the globe. Understanding the Fair Information Practice Principles and how they should be implemented is critical to comply with the various privacy laws that protect personal information.

 **In order to be in line with Fair Information Practices we will take the following responsive action, should a data breach occur:**

We will notify the users via email

 **•** Within 3 business days

We also agree to the individual redress principle, which requires that individuals have a right to pursue legally enforceable rights against data collectors and processors who fail to adhere to the law. This principle requires not only that individuals have enforceable rights against data users, but also that individuals have recourse to courts or a government agency to investigate and/or prosecute non-compliance by data processors.

 **CAN SPAM Act**

The CAN-SPAM Act is a law that sets the rules for commercial email, establishes requirements for commercial messages, gives recipients the right to have emails stopped from being sent to them, and spells out tough penalties for violations.

 **We collect your email address in order to:**

  * Market to our mailing list or continue to send emails to our clients after the original transaction has occurred

 **To be in accordance with CANSPAM we agree to the following:**

 **•** NOT use false, or misleading subjects or email addresses

 **•** Identify the message as an advertisement in some reasonable way

 **•** Include the physical address of our business or site headquarters

 **•** Monitor third party email marketing services for compliance, if one is used.

 **•** Honor opt-out/unsubscribe requests quickly

 **•** Allow users to unsubscribe by using the link at the bottom of each email

 **  
If at any time you would like to unsubscribe from receiving future emails, you can**

 **•** Follow the instructions at the bottom of each email to unsubscribe

and we will promptly remove you from **ALL** correspondence.

 **Contacting Us**

If there are any questions regarding this privacy policy you may contact us using the information below.

https://independenttravelcats.com

Travel Cats Media Ltd  
C/o High Royd Business Services Limited  
B B I C  
Innovation Way  
Barnsley  
South Yorkshire  
S75 1JL

jessica@independenttravelcats.com

Last Edited on 2019-04-06
